SIMRAN AMIN

EMAIL: simranamin@hotmail.com PHONE: 07955375777

PROFILE

I am a 2021 graduate of Dental Surgery at the University of Liverpool where I graduated with honours and achieved distinctions in both oral diseases and oral health. Prior to this, I graduated from the University of Cambridge in 2017 where I studied Natural Sciences with a special interest in pathology and pharmacology. Alongside my clinical training I enjoy working in medical education which includes over 4 years of experience working remotely as an editor to provide digital examination resources for prospective medical/dental school applicants alongside written guides for onboarding new writers. With a strong digital, scientific and communicative background I am very interested in branching out and building on my strengths within alternative careers, particularly relating to data analysis, web development, editing and UI design.

EDUCATION

001-0001		
2017-2021	University of L	iverpool

Bachelor of Dental Surgery with Honours (Graduate Entry Pathway)

Distinction in Oral Diseases Distinction in Oral Health

2014-2017 Churchill College, University of Cambridge

Natural Sciences - Bachelor of Arts with Honours

Part II: High 2:1 (69%) - Pharmacology

Part 1B: High 2:1 (69%) - Pathology, Pharmacology, Developmental Biology Part 1A: High 2:1 (67%) - Physiology, Cellular Biology, Chemistry, Maths

2007–2014 The Tiffin Girls' School, Kingston upon Thames

A-levels: A2 Biology (A*) A2 Chemistry (A*) A2 Maths (A*), AS Art (A)

GCSEs: 11, 10 at grade A* including Maths, English Language, French, Spanish OCR Level 2 Certificate in Creative iMedia (Website design, Video editing)

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

2021	MFDS Part 1 (Royal College of Surgeons of England)
2020	ABAOMS Essay Prize
	Liverpool winner for essay titled 'The Impact of Human Factors on Oral Surgery'
2019	Dental Alumni Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Oral Science & Medicine Knowledge Examinations
2019	Mark Ball Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 3 rd BDS Evidence Based Virtual Case Report Presentation
2018	Robert Grieve Memorial Prize
	Highest overall mark for 2 nd BDS Oral Science and Medicine Critical Reasoning Paper
2017	Churchill College Academic Prize
2211	For attaining high examination results in Part II pharmacology
2014	Tiffin Girls' School Biology Prize

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

2022-ongoing Family Dental Practice: Trainee Dentist (8 months)

2017-2021 Medify: UCAT Abstract Reasoning Editor (4 years)

 Reviewed and edited questions submitted by question writers to ensure clarity of written explanations and associated graphics

- Responsible for managing and resolving web content problems reported by Medify users
- Remotely onboarded new members of the team and created guidance documentation to support new question writers

2016 **IDM: Creative Data Academy** (3 day workshop)

 Selected to participate in an introduction to the field of digital marketing involving a series of lectures and participating in data analysis projects for companies such as Mercedes Benz and Feel Unique

OTHER POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY

2018-2019 University of Liverpool: Student Mentor

 Point of support for four first year graduate entry dental students for academic and clinical advice

2015-2017 University of Cambridge: President of Churchill College Art Society

- Organised and lead weekly drawing, painting and origami sessions
- Commissioned by Churchill College to illustrate a Fresher's week backdrop
- Managed annual budget for art expenses

ARTICLES AND PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Amin, S. (2018). 'Are you considering Graduate Dentistry?', *UniAdmissions*, Available at: https://www.uniadmissions.co.uk/application-guides/considering-graduate-entry-dentistry/
- 2. Amadeu de Oliveira, F., MacVinish, L. J., Amin, S., Herath, D., Jeggle, P., Mela, I., Pieri, M., Sharma, C., Jarvis, G. E., Levy, F. M., Santesso, M. R., Khan, Z. N., Leite, A. L., Oliveira, R. C., Buzalaf, M. A. R. and Edwardson, J. M. (2018) 'The effect of fluoride on the structure, function, and proteome of intestinal epithelia', *Environmental Toxicology*, 33(1), pp. 63-71. doi: 10.1002/TOX.22495.

DIGITAL SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Adobe Photoshop and Illustrator | Procreate | Figma | Microsoft Powerpoint, Excel and Word

PORTFOLIO (under development): http://simranamin.com/

2023 freeCodeCamp: Responsive Web Design Certification

 Learned basic HTML/CSS to create a variety of webpages including a survey form, tribute page, product landing page, technical documentation page and personal portfolio

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Cooking new recipes
- Visiting cafés, museums and outdoor spaces
- Digital drawing (Photoshop, Procreate) and traditional painting
- Tennis, pilates and running
- Learning about personality theory and self-development
- Cats, dogs, frogs and insects!